Ashutosh Kapoor

Software Developer

Pengaluru, India

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/ashutosh-kapoor-0499ab192/



PROFILE

A budding developer with about one and a half year of experience in front-end tech stack. I have a strong web performance and functionality implementation. I am motivated to learn new skills with a passion for software development.



PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Roost.ai, Software Developer

January 2022 - present | Bengaluru, India

- Led the development of Roost's cutting-edge product using React and Nest JS, enabling clients to use AI technology in generating unit, functional, and non-functional test cases for their source code.
- Engineered an Environment as a Service (EaaS) and a dashboard, for clients to easily operate command line interface functionalities through a visually intuitive interface.
- Integrated product with third-party applications using RESTful APIs.
- Upgraded and integrated Roost for clients, ensuring compliance with evolving industry standards and enhancing their software development processes.
- Implemented backend driven approach for UI development, coordinating with team to analyse, design and deliver within timeline.
- Revamped UI and refactored state management using JavaScript object model and cleaned up existing code-base, resulting in a remarkable 40% reduction in code complexity, increased turnaround speed and decreased load time.

LiVert France, Web Developer Intern

May 2021 - August 2021

• Worked as a Web Developer for a French Startup Shopmate now known as LiVert France. LiVert France is a 100% free solution to get a free and more ecological delivery on all online purchases.

SKILLS



PROJECTS

The Webfolio ∂

- Developed a visually appealing and fully scalable website using React, JavaScript and Sanity for the backend integration.
- Created sections for live projects, skills and profile along with a contact me section with social media handles, facilitating seamless communication with potential clients and employers.
- Utilized React framer motion to enhance the overall user experience and engagement.

Fitness Club - A Fitness Web App ∂

 A full fledged fitness web-app personalized for user to find the perfect exercises for them. It also suggests similar to the one user is looking for and videos on YouTube related to tit.

YouTube Clone *∂*

• A fully working YouTube clone with a seamless video playback experience with the supports of all the YouTube features.

EDUCATION

BTech, The LNM Institute of Information Technology

August 2018 - May 2022

Undergraduate in Computer Science and Engineering